AMMAR ALASADI

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

571-242-1832 WWW.AMMARCODE.COM ALASADI.AMMAR@GMAIL.COM

ABOUT

I am a web developer with a background in languages and communication. My goal as a developer is to find creative solutions and enhance the user experience. I value communication and planning to guide my progress in development. I am a team player with a love of sharing experience and learning.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, DOM
- Ruby On Rails, ORM
- React, Redux, AngularJs, Express
- MEAN Stack, ODM
- SQL and NoSQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- MVC Framework
- JavaScript JQuery
- Agile, Scrum
- API's, AJAX, JSON
- RESTful API Design

LINKS

GitHub: ammaralasadi1

LinkedIn: https://goo.gl/wz16Sg Portfolio: www.ammarcode.com

EDUCATION

General Assembly Washington, DC

Web Development Immersive Feb - June 2017

University of Technology Baghdad

A.A. in Architecture Design 2006 - 2008

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Student March - June 2017

I learned web development in agile, scrum environment with a focus on functional programming. I developed full-stack apps is javaScript, Ruby on Rails, MEAN, React / Redux and Node.js. I had the opportunity to work on a group project to build interactive weather and transportation application for DC metro in Angular.js and Ruby on Rails. During my studies, I became familiar with Git and GitHub workflow. Improved on the reliability and readability of source code by following best practices. Focused on planning, modeling and wireframing of web applications.

Self Employed

Arabic linguist 2014 - 2017

I translated material in target languages with a focus on accuracy and details. I also worked with a team of translators to deliver projects, meet deadlines and guarantee client satisfaction. I was heavily involved in resource planning, developing schedules and time estimating. I managed a team of five translators and assigned tasks based on the skills of each team member. I was fortunate to develop a cultural training guide for deployed government officials to help them communicate efficiently and ensure their safety.

CYRACOM

Arabic Interpreter 2014 - 2017

I Interpreted for a wide range of sectors including medical, legal and social services. I also provided clients cultural education to help them make informed decisions. My main focus was to create a fluid experience between parties and eliminated the language barrier. I was grateful to help clients elevate their concerns by communicating their needs directly.